{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Jimmy Carter","incorrectAnswers":["George W. Bush","Ronald Reagan","Grover Cleveland"],"question":"Who was the 39th president of the USA, in term during the period 1977–1981?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ramen","incorrectAnswers":["Ceviche","Plov","Chilli Crab"],"question":"Which of these dishes would you most expect to find in Japan?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"You can't handle the truth!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Just keep swimming.\"","\"Of all the gin joints in all the towns in all the world, she walks into mine.\"","\"As God is my witness, I'll never be hungry again.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'A Few Good Men'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Jenny","incorrectAnswers":["A Soar","A Doe","A Vixen"],"question":"What would you call a female donkey?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Medusa","incorrectAnswers":["Minotaur","Harpy","Siren"],"question":"Which Ancient Greek creature had snakes for hair?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kinshasa","incorrectAnswers":["Gitega","Niamey","N'Djamena"],"question":"What is the capital city of Democratic Republic of the Congo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Gold","incorrectAnswers":["Silver","Platinum","Diamond"],"question":"What is the traditional gift for a 50th wedding anniversary?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"the age of the Earth","incorrectAnswers":["the biosphere and its relations to the lithosphere and atmosphere","the functions of the nervous system","the preparation of books and manuscripts"],"question":"What is Geochronology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Mississippi","incorrectAnswers":["The Colorado River","The Rio Grande","The Thames"],"question":"In the 19th century, which river's Bloody Island was a popular duelling site since it was out of the jurisdiction of both Missouri and Illinois?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Orson Welles","incorrectAnswers":["John Travolta","Bruce Willis","Robert De Niro"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Charles Foster Kane in Citizen Kane?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Aqueous vapors","incorrectAnswers":["Insects","The nervous system","Weather"],"question":"What is Atmology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oceania","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Europe","Asia"],"question":"The country of Samoa is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Formosa","incorrectAnswers":["Feilu","Jagary","Peking"],"question":"What was Taiwan formerly known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Vicks","incorrectAnswers":["Pfizer","Johnson & Johnson","Bayer"],"question":"What company produces a topical ointment called VapoRub to help with coughs?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Saudi Arabia","incorrectAnswers":["Kazakhstan","Liberia","Iceland"],"question":"Which country's flag fits the description of 'Green, with large white script and a sword.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Uganda","incorrectAnswers":["Guinea","Bangladesh","Solomon Islands"],"question":"Kampala is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Stravinsky","incorrectAnswers":["Tchaikovsky","Prokofiev","Debussy"],"question":"Whose ballet music includes Petrushka and The Rite of Spring?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mali","incorrectAnswers":["Sierra Leone","Togo","Benin"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Ivory Coast?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Pennsylvania","incorrectAnswers":["Virginia","Maryland","New York"],"question":"In which US State was the site of the 1863 Battle of Gettysburg?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jingle All The Way","incorrectAnswers":["The Santa Clause","Miracle on 34th Street","Bad Santa"],"question":"Which Popular Christmas Movie Featured A Must Have Toy Called 'Turbo Man''","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Vin maison ","incorrectAnswers":["Vin chateau","Vin dom","Vin chambre"],"question":"How would you say 'house wine' in 'French'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Sandwich Islands","incorrectAnswers":["James Islands","Victoria Islands","Brittania Islands"],"question":"When Cook Discovered The Hawaiian Islands What Did He Name Them?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A slacker seeks restitution for a rug ruined by debt collectors.","incorrectAnswers":["On a journey to find the cure for a curse, a boy finds himself in the middle of a war.","After awakening from a coma, a former assassin wreaks vengeance on those who betrayed her.","The son of a former boxer is trained by his father for a mixed martial arts tournament."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The Big Lebowski?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Fyodor Dostoyevsky","incorrectAnswers":["Vladimir Nabokov","Leo Tolstoy","Mikhail Bulgakov"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Crime and Punishment'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Spain","incorrectAnswers":["Morocco","Barbados","Mauritania"],"question":"Madrid is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Pleasantville","incorrectAnswers":["The Incredible Mr. Limpet","The Ghost and Mr. Chicken","Hot Lead and Cold Feet"],"question":"In which 1998 movie did Don Knotts play a magical TV repairman who transports two siblings to a black and white town?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Uranus","incorrectAnswers":["Mars","Jupiter","Venus"],"question":"What is the planet whose list of moons includes Oberon and Titania?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mark Wahlberg","incorrectAnswers":["Ralph Fiennes","Brian Cox","Michael Douglas"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including The Fighter and Ted?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"An archaeologist is hired by the government to find the Ark of the Covenant.","incorrectAnswers":["On a journey to find the cure for a curse, a boy finds himself in the middle of a war.","A Tramp struggles to live in modern industrial society with the help of a young homeless woman.","A 12-year-old is taken in by a professional assassin after her family is murdered."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Raiders of the Lost Ark?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Which American musician released the album 'HIStory: Past, Present and Future, Book I'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bill Murray","incorrectAnswers":["Jeff Bridges","John Belushi","Joe Pesci"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Carl Spackler in Caddyshack?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The thereputic effects of bathing","incorrectAnswers":["Plasma","Balinese culture","Victims of crime"],"question":"What is balneology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Chad","incorrectAnswers":["São Tomé and Príncipe","Benin","Niger"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Cameroon?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hypertext Markup Language","incorrectAnswers":["High Tech Machine Language","Hypertext Transfer Model","Hardware Technology Marker Language"],"question":"What does HTML stand for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Rocky","incorrectAnswers":["The Godfather","Jaws","Star Wars"],"question":"Which 1970s movie, featuring Sylvester Stallone, was re-released under the rhyming title \"The Italian Stallion\"?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Merchant of Venice'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Athens","incorrectAnswers":["Rome","Florence","Crete"],"question":"Where is the Parthenon located?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Tsunami","incorrectAnswers":["Kahuna","Overflow","Grand Masif"],"question":"What is the name for a great wave resulting from an earthquake?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Meryl Streep","incorrectAnswers":["Cate Blanchett","Nicole Kidman","Natalie Portman"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including The Deer Hunter and Lemony Snicket's A Series of Unfortunate Events?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Starsky and Hutch","incorrectAnswers":["Cagney and Lacey","Simon and Simon","Tango and Cash"],"question":"Which TV show followed a pair of streetwise cops played by Paul Michael Glaser and David Soul?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Semen","incorrectAnswers":["Digestive proteins","Blood cells","Aphrodisiacs"],"question":"Which of these does the prostate contribute to the production of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Louis Daguerre","incorrectAnswers":["John Logie Baird","Thomas Edison","Emile Berliner"],"question":"Who Took The First Practical Photograph?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Elementary, my dear Watson.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Keep your friends close, but your enemies closer.\"","\"My mother thanks you. My father thanks you. My sister thanks you. And I thank you.\"","\"My precious.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Naypyidaw","incorrectAnswers":["Sana'a","Banjul","Gitega"],"question":"What is the capital city of Myanmar?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Motorsports","incorrectAnswers":["American Football","Ice Hockey","Horse Racing"],"question":"What sport would you associate with Le Mans 24 Hours?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Mary I","incorrectAnswers":["Mary II","Richard III","Henry I"],"question":"Who was the monarch of England during the time period 1553-1558?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The internal structures of stars","incorrectAnswers":["Caves","Church architecture","Meteors"],"question":"What is asteroseismology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Duff ","incorrectAnswers":["Luff","Muff","Buff"],"question":"Which brand of beer does Homer Simpson drink regularly?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Oompa Loompas","incorrectAnswers":["Ongo Bongos","Oogie Boogies","Pogre Ogres"],"question":"What are the name of the factory workers who love cacao beans in a classic children's book by Roald Dahl?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Atalanta","incorrectAnswers":["Detroit","Miami","Houston"],"question":"In Baseball where do the braves come from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Dutch","incorrectAnswers":["English","Swahili","Arabic"],"question":"What language is Afrikaans closely related to?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Mika","Elton John"],"question":"Which British musician released the song 'The Man Who Sold the World'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Sun Records","incorrectAnswers":["Moon Records","Sky Records","Cloud Records"],"question":"For which label did Elvis first record?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kristin Scott Thomas","incorrectAnswers":["Glenn Close","Reese Witherspoon","Melissa Leo"],"question":"Which actress has appeared in films including The English Patient and Gosford Park?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bob Marley and The Wailers","incorrectAnswers":["Lenny Kravitz","Andy Williams","The Guess Who"],"question":"The song 'I Shot the Sheriff' had a well-known cover by Eric Clapton, but who recorded the original?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Chainsmokers","incorrectAnswers":["The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American EDM Duo released the song 'Don't Let Me Down'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1975","incorrectAnswers":["1957","1963","1969"],"question":"In which year was the digital camera invented?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Michael Schumacher","incorrectAnswers":["Lewis Hamilton","Ayrton Senna","Mika Häkkinen"],"question":"Who Won Nine Formula One Grand Prix Races In 2000?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Rain Man","incorrectAnswers":["The Accidental Tourist","Dangerous Liaisons","Mississippi Burning"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1988?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vietnam","incorrectAnswers":["France","UK","Guatemala"],"question":"In which country would you find Ha Long Bay?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ammonia","incorrectAnswers":["Nitrogen dioxide","Hydrogen sulfide","Methane"],"question":"What is the name of the compound made of nitrogen and hydrogen, that is commonly used in fertilizers?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Spain","Brazil"],"question":"Which country won the 1938 FIFA World Cup, hosted in France?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Norway","incorrectAnswers":["Estonia","Italy","Sweden"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Geirangerfjord and Nærøyfjord?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Penélope Cruz","incorrectAnswers":["Amy Adams","Viola Davis","Taraji P. Henson"],"question":"Who won the 2008 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Maria Elena in Vicky Cristina Barcelona?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Mrs White, Miss Scarlet, Mrs Peacock","incorrectAnswers":["Mrs Plum, Miss Jade, Mrs Scarlett","Mrs White, Miss Gold, Mrs Green","Miss Silver, Mrs Pink, Mrs Indigo"],"question":"Name The 3 Female Characters In The Game Cluedo","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Iron Maiden","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Squeeze"],"question":"Which English heavy metal band released the album 'Killers'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belgium","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Finland","Spain"],"question":"Which European country is home to the Sonian Forest and the towns of Tervuren and Waterloo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1956","incorrectAnswers":["1932","1940","1921"],"question":"When was the first chemotherapy treatment?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Andorra","incorrectAnswers":["Liechtenstein","United Kingdom","San Marino"],"question":"Which of these countries borders France?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Leonardo DiCaprio","incorrectAnswers":["Matt Damon","Johnny Depp","Brad Pitt"],"question":"Which actor played Meryl Streep's son in the 1996 film 'Marvin's Room' before starring in 'The Beach'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Francisco Coronado","incorrectAnswers":["Francisco Pizzaro","Hernando de Soto","Jose Garrido"],"question":"Which Spanish conquistador's expedition marked the first European sighting of the Grand Canyon?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Philadelphia Phillies","incorrectAnswers":["Philadelphia Brewers","Philadelphia Crew","Philadelphia Orioles"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in Philadelphia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde","incorrectAnswers":["Frankenstein","The Picture of Dorian Gray","Wuthering Heights"],"question":"Which literary work by Robert Louis Stevenson is frequently interpreted as an examination of the duality of human nature?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ribbon pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Stuffed pasta","Tubular pasta","Shaped pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is pappardelle?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"2010","incorrectAnswers":["2016","2004","1998"],"question":"When did the Arab Spring topple a number of governments?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Toga! Toga!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"With great power comes great responsiblity.\"","\"Frankly, my dear, I don't give a damn.\"","\"Soylent Green is people!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'National Lampoon's Animal House'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"NaOCI","incorrectAnswers":["Fe2O3","CH4","NaHCO3"],"question":"What is the chemical formula for sodium hypochlorite?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Table Salt","incorrectAnswers":["QuickSilver","Baking Soda","Cream of tartar"],"question":"What is the common name for sodium chloride?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Why don't you come up sometime and see me?\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Yo, Adrian!\"","\"What’s the most you ever lost on a coin toss?\"","\"Yo, Adrian!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'She Done Him Wrong'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Turkey","incorrectAnswers":["Israel","Jordan","Bahrain"],"question":"In which country is the city of Antalya?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Nicoli Machiavelli","incorrectAnswers":["John Locke","Simon Bolivar","John F. Kennedy"],"question":"Which influential historical person was a diplomat and Renaissance writer, considered the father of political science?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Azerbaijan","incorrectAnswers":["Ukraine","Georgia","Tajikistan"],"question":"In which country is the city of Baku?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Parma ","incorrectAnswers":["Genoa","Venice","Florence"],"question":"Which Italian city gave its name to a cheese and a type of ham?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Golf","incorrectAnswers":["Tennis","Cricket","Rugby"],"question":"With what sport is Jack Nicklaus associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Taxi Driver","incorrectAnswers":["Blue Velvet","Wall Street","To Kill a Mockingbird"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Travis Bickle'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Indonesia","incorrectAnswers":["Malaysia","Thailand","The Philippines"],"question":"Which country was previously known as the Dutch East Indies?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gruyere","incorrectAnswers":["Feta","Cheddar","Mozzarella"],"question":"What type of cheese would you be most likely to add to the top of a classic French onion soup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Adventure of the Red-Headed League'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kate Bush","incorrectAnswers":["David Bowie","John Lennon","George Michael"],"question":"Which British recording artist, singer, songwriter, musician and record producer released the studio album 'The Kick Inside'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Louisa May Alcott","incorrectAnswers":["Edgar Allan Poe","Nathaniel Hawthorne","Stephen King"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Little Women'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A landlubber","incorrectAnswers":["A seadog","A scurvy","A sea shanty"],"question":"What is the nautical term for a person unfamiliar with the sea?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Snooker","Motor racing","Ice Hockey"],"question":"With which sport is Usain Bolt associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter and dancer released the album 'Bad'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Francis Bacon","incorrectAnswers":["Jean-Paul Sartre","Socrates","William of Ockham"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Things alter for the worse spontaneously, if they be not altered for the better designedly'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"A type of apple ","incorrectAnswers":["A type of pear","A type of peach","A type of apricot"],"question":"What is a 'Blenheim Orange'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Don Cheadle","incorrectAnswers":["Josh Brolin","Paul Bettany","Vin Diesel"],"question":"The role of James \"Rhodey\" Rhodes in the Marvel Cinematic Universe is played by which actor?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Marlon Brando","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Caine","Laurence Olivier","Peter O'Toole"],"question":"Who won the 1972 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Don Vito Corleone in The Godfather?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Anise","incorrectAnswers":["Cinnamon","Ginger","Rosemary"],"question":"Which herb is used to flavour Pernod?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Java","incorrectAnswers":["Flark","Goku","Anon"],"question":"Which of these is a popular programming language?","difficulty":"medium"},